[
  {
    "Question": "What are the dependability attributes?",
    "Answer": "*Availability: readiness for correct service\n*Reliability: Survival probability\n*Saftey: absence of catastrophics consequences\n*Confidentiality: Absence of unautorized desclosure of information\n*Integrity: absence of improper system alterations\nMaintanability: abiility to undergo modifications and repairs"
  },
  {
    "Question": "How do you calculate the reliability of two components that are \n*series\nand\n*paralel?",
    "Answer": "Rseries = R1*R2\nRparalel = 1-(1-R1)'(1-r2)'"
  },
  {
    "Question": "How do you calculate availability of a system?",
    "Answer": "Availability= uptime/uptime+downtime"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain Rate of Occurance Of Failure",
    "Answer": "= 0.002 means: 2 failures are likely in each 1000 operational time units"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain Hazard avoidance",
    "Answer": "This type of system is designed so that hazards are avoided. For example, a safe cutting system equipped with two control buttons, wherethe two buttons can be operated by using separate hands."
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain Hazard detection and remova",
    "Answer": "In a system where the system can detect and remedy the hazard once detected without affecting performance"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Damage limitation",
    "Answer": "The system have the ability to mimimize the damage once it occurs. Autimatic fire extinguisher"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain Risk",
    "Answer": "EFc(expected cost of failure) = Pf(probability of failure) * Cf(Cost of failure)"
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain and do FMECA for a system",
    "Answer": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain Reliaility vs Availability vs Saftey",
    "Answer": "*A system that is shut off is:\n-not very reliable\n-not vary available\n-but is probably very safe(hahaha)\n*High availability systems pus to be up and running 99.999...\n*Saftey critical systems dont aim to optimize uptime. They can intentionally shut down to prevent injury or loss of life"
  }
]
